cushwake.com 2006-12-31

# Cushman & Wakefield - Global real estate solutions

This website is operated by Cushman & Wakefield, Inc., our group companies, international partnerships and affiliated organisations (including alliance and associate offices) ("C&W"),  

### Your privacy

C&W ("we", "our" or "us") are part of one of the world's largest commercial real estate consultancies. We recognize that when you choose to provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner. That's why we have put a policy in place to protect your personal information. Please read on for more details about our privacy practices.

### What information do we collect? How do we use it?

At times we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information. Generally this information is requested when you register for an online service, when you provide information in connection with an online transaction or when you contact us in relation to the site or our services. We may gather information about you:

  * When you register with us we ask for information such as your name, email address, and contact details. We keep a record of this information. This is necessary for us to recognise you as a registered site user. We may keep a record of your preferences so that we can tailor our offers and services to you.
  * Once you have registered, you may join our discussion forums and we may hold information about you from your use of such discussion forums. You will be asked to agree to our Website Terms and Conditions. See link at foot of page.
  * When you enter a competition, register for a client event or other promotional event, we may ask for your name, address, telephone number and email address so we can administer the event.
  * If you purchase something from our site such as a research report, we will need your name, address, telephone number and email so that we can process your order. We will also need your payment details which we will ensure are kept securely.
  * If you choose to give us personal information via the site that we or our business partners may need - to correspond with you for example, we will let you know how we will use such information. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes.
  * We will use your personal details and information we obtain from other sources to provide you with information about our services, for administration and customer services, for marketing, to analyse your purchasing preferences and to ensure that the content, services and advertising that we offer are tailored to your needs and interests. We may keep your information for a reasonable period for these purposes. We may need to share your information with our service providers and agents for these purposes. We may disclose personal data in order to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
  * We intend to continue improving the content and function of our website. For this reason, we may monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us improve the design and layout of our site and provide content of interest to you.

### Use of cookies, web beacons and other devices

We may use information obtained about you from cookies, files which are sent by us to your computer or other access device, which we may access when you open an email from us or visit our site in future.

We are able to do this by including web beacons (also known as clear GIFs or web bugs) in our emails. We use cookies and web beacons so that we can identify our users and personalise the site and our services whenever possible and to track the success of our marketing campaigns. The devices store small pieces of information about visitors which means that on future visits to our site, we can identify past visitors and welcome them back and that if you open an email from us we can see which pages of our site you visit.

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Our cookies will have the file names [X.@cushwake.com.txt,Y.cushwake.com..txt] . If you want to stop cookies being stored on your computer in future, please refer to your browser manufacturer's instructions by clicking "Help" in your browser menu. Further information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at www.AboutCookies.org Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our site.

Our web beacons do not store additional information on your computer but, by communicating with our cookies on your computer, they can tell us when you have opened our email. If you object to web beacons, we recommend that you follow the instructions for deleting existing cookies and disabling future cookies. We will still know how many of our emails are opened and we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier of your computer or other access device; but we will not identify you as an individual. With or without web beacons, your IP address may also be logged when you visit our site.

### How do we use your information for marketing?

We may share your information within our international partnerships, group companies and affiliated organisations and with our business partners for marketing purposes or we may send you information about other organisations' goods and services. We or any business partners may contact you, directly or via our agents, by mail, telephone, fax, email, SMS or other electronic messaging service with offers of goods and services or information that may be of interest to you. By providing us with your fax number, telephone numbers or email address you consent to being contacted by these methods for these purposes. If you do not wish to receive marketing information either from us or our business partners please indicate this where requested on the registration or contact form or contact us using the details below.

### Your consent and other people's information

By providing us with your personal information, you consent to our processing your personal data, including sensitive personal data, for the above purposes. You also consent to our transferring your information to countries or jurisdictions which do not provide the same level of data protection as the country in which you are based, for example the UK, if necessary for the above purposes. If we do make such a transfer, we or they will, if appropriate, put a contract in place to ensure that your information is protected.

If you provide us with information about another person for example if you use the Email a Friend facility, you confirm that they have appointed you to act for them, to consent to the processing of their personal data including sensitive personal data and that you have informed them of our identity and the purposes (as set out above) for which their personal data will be processed. When we first contact them we may tell them where we got their information from.

### How do we protect your information?

[We offer the use of a secure server when you place orders or access your account information. [SSL] (the secure server software) encrypts your information before it is sent to us.] We take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

### Disclaimer

We link to a wide variety of other sites and we display advertisements from third parties on our site. We are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of these sites and third party advertisers, nor for the way in which information about their users is treated. In particular, unless expressly stated, we are not agents for these sites or advertisers nor are we authorised to make representations on their behalf.  

### Passwords

In order to bring you more personalized services, we may ask you to establish one or more passwords to gain access to certain services or sections in either our website or the website(s) of other suppliers whose products or services are available to you via a link from our website. As such, we may share the password information you provide us with those other authorised suppliers. You are solely responsible for the control and use of each password you create.

### Other Information

You are entitled to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) and to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected.

For quality control and training purposes, we may monitor or record your communications with us.

### When and how to contact us

If your personal details change, if you change your mind about any of your marketing preferences or if you have any queries about how we use your information, please let us know by contacting our Mailing Exclusion Team at: [unsubscribe@eur.cushwake.com](mailto:unsubscribe@eur.cushwake.com)

### Canada's Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy is based on, and complies with, Canada's _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ ("PIPEDA"), which includes the Ten Privacy Principles outlined in the Canadian Standards Association _Model Code for the Protection of Personal Privacy_. For more information about this legislation, please visit the official Web site of the Privacy Commission of Canada at [http://www.privcom.gc.ca](http://www.privcom.gc.ca/). All of our employees who have access to personal information must adhere to the Privacy Policy and related procedures. To this end, we have appointed a Privacy Officer to ensure compliance by all employees. "Personal Information" means information about an identifiable individual client. This may include without limitation, the individual's name, home address, e-mail address, age, gender, income, personal preferences and other information about his or her family. Personal information does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization. 

### The Ten Principles of Privacy

The following ten principles govern our actions as they relate to the use of our clients' personal information:  
**Principle 1 – Accountability**  
We are accountable for all personal information in our possession or custody, including personal information disclosed to third parties for purposes of providing services requested by our clients or employees.

**Principle 2 – Identifying Purposes**  
We will inform our clients of the purposes for which we are collecting any personal information, before or at the time the information is collected.

**Principle 3 – Consent**  
Our policy is to require our agents to obtain consent from our clients before or when we collect, use or disclose their personal information. A client's consent can be expressed, implied, or given through an authorized representative. A client can withdraw consent at any time, with certain exceptions. We may, however, collect, use or disclose personal information without the client' knowledge or consent in exceptional circumstances where such collection, use or disclosure is permitted or required by law.

**Principle 4 – Limiting Collection  
**The information collected from the client will be limited to those details necessary for the purposes we have identified to the client. Information will be collected by fair and lawful means.

**Principle 5 – Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention**  
Personal information will only be used or disclosed for the purpose for which it was collectedunless the client has otherwise consented, or when it is required or permitted by law. In certain exceptional circumstances, we may have a legal duty or right to disclose personal information without client knowledge or consent with respect to matters that concern the company's or the public's interest.

**Principle 6 – Accuracy**  
We will keep personal information as accurate, complete and current as necessary to fulfill the identified purposes for which it was collected. Clients may have this information amended where it is found to be inaccurate or incomplete.

**Principle 7 – Safeguarding Personal Information**  
Personal information is safeguarded using measures appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.

**Principle 8 – Openness**  
We will make information available to our clients about the policies and procedures we use to manage personal information. Clients have access to this information through our Web site, or through alternate means if requested.

**Principle 9 – Client Access  
**Upon written request, a client will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of their personal information, and will be given access to it. We will respond to such requests as efficiently as possible.  If we are prohibited from providing such access we will explain the reasons for the lack of access, except where prohibited by law.

**Principle 10 – Addressing Client Complaints and Suggestions  
**Clients may challenge C&W LePage's compliance with this Privacy Policy. C&W LePage has policies and procedures to receive, investigate and respond to client's complaints and questions. Clients may contact C&W LePage's Privacy Officer to express any concerns or to request access to their personal information.  The contact information for this individual is provided below. 

### When Can We Disclose Personal Information?

We are obliged to keep clients personal information confidential _except under the following circumstances:_

  * **-When Authorized by the client**
  * **-When Required by Law**
  * **-When Permitted by Law**

### With Whom We May Share Information

  * **Employees**  
In the course of daily operations, access to sensitive personal information is limited to those employees with a legitimate reason for accessing it. As a condition of their employment, our employees are required to follow all applicable laws and regulations, including this Privacy Policy.  
Unauthorized use or disclosure of confidential client information by one of our employees is prohibited and may result in disciplinary measures
  * **Third Party Suppliers  
**We may engage and coordinate third party suppliers to provide us or our employees with certain services offered through C&W LePage We may use client contact information to conduct an evaluation of our performance on their behalf.  Such suppliers are only given the information that is needed to provide the specific service for which we contract them to provide.  Suppliers are contractually bound to protect the confidentiality of personal information, and they are prohibited from doing anything with this information that we have not authorized them to do. They are required to treat personal information in a manner consistent with our Privacy Policy.
  * **Sale of Business  
**We may transfer client's personally identifiable information to a third party in connection with a sale, merger or other disposition (whether of assets, stock or otherwise) of our business.

### How We Safeguard Information

C&W LePage has extensive controls in place to maintain the security of its information and information systems. Client files are stored according to the sensitivity of the information contained therein. Appropriate controls (such as restricted access) are placed on our computer systems and data processing procedures.  Physical access to areas where personal information is gathered, processed or stored is limited to authorized employees.

### Opting Out

In order to provide clients with our services and products, we may, with their consent, share their personal information with other C&W LePage  affiliates.  Should a client not want to receive promotional materials from or have their personal information shared with these companies please contact C&W LePage at the address, phone number or email address provided below:  
**Address:** 33 Yonge Street, suite 1000, Toronto, Ontario M5E 1S9  
**Phone Number:** (416) 359-2751  
**Email Address:** [privacy@ca.cushwake.com](mailto:privacy@royallepage.com)

### Questions, Concerns and Complaints

For Questions, concerns or complaints about personal information, or about our Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Officer using the contact information provide below:  
**Privacy Officer:** Beth Connor  
**Contact Information:** (416) 359-2365 or [privacy@ca.cushwake.com](mailto:privacy@royallepage.com)
